翻譯：allenlovestar
翻譯：gkall
翻譯：wyk8818
校對：彼岸荼蘼
時間軸：wxw996
時間軸：憑陵新月
后期：Sung1219
故事發生在德克薩斯州
露絲
Ruth.
等等啊  露絲
Hey, Ruth.
-你上哪兒去  -回家
- Where are you going? - Home.
-家不在這邊  -不回我家
- Home's the other way. - Not mine.
你要回娘家啊
Are you going back to your mom's?
那得走15英里路
It's a 15-mile walk.
我知道
I know how far it is.
好吧  我跟你一起走
All right. Well, then, I'll just walk with you.
你愛干啥干啥
You do whatever you want.
我想帶你回我們家
What I want to do is take you back to our house.
你為什么和弗雷迪說你要自己動手
Why did you tell Freddy you were gonna strike out on your own?
我不記得說過這話啊  不過真要說了
I don't think I said that, but if I did,
我說的"自己"也是指我們倆
when I say, "On my own," I mean you and me.
一直都是咱倆
I always mean you and me.
你是要甩了我嗎
You gonna leave me?
沒有啊  我不會甩你
No, I'm not gonna leave you.
沒人要甩你
Nobody's leaving any...
老娘會先甩了你
'Cause I will leave you first.
有意思嗎
It's not... funny.
我不會離開你的
I'm not gonna leave you.
你也一樣離不開我
You're not gonna leave me.
如果你真走了  我就跟著你
Because if you do, I'll just follow you.
我不想去坐牢
I don't want to go to jail.
不會坐牢的
Not going to jail.
你那破地方根本不算是個家
And that shack ain't a home.
我在想辦法啊
Well, I'm working on it.
我覺得自己懷孕了
And I think I'm gonna have a baby.
我們要有小孩了嗎
We're gonna have a baby?
你沒抓狂嗎
You're not mad?
沒有啊
I'm not mad.
我媽會幫忙養著的
No, my mama will raise it.
我能偷個吻嗎
Can I steal a kiss?
別鬧了  怪癢癢的
Stop it. That tickles.
對胎兒不是應該唱唱歌什么的嗎
That's what you're supposed to do, is sing songs.
就說說話吧
Just talk.
你累嗎
Are you tired?
好了
All right.
我不會有事的
I'll be fine.
我去去就回
I'll be back in five minutes.
我們正在追捕嫌疑人
We've got a little bit of a chase on our hands here...
我跟你說  走進去
I tell you, walking into there,
你會覺得自己要去見魔鬼
you feel like you're meeting the devil.
所有警車請準備支援
All cars for backup.
重復一遍  所有警車  所有警車
I repeat, all cars, all cars...
-所有警車  -該死  服務員買單
- any and all cars. - Shit. All right. Check, hon.
我中彈了
I'm hit!
我打著人了
I shot someone.
我好像打中了誰
I think I shot someone.
沒事的
It's okay.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-我打著人了  -糟糕了
- I think I shot someone. - Oh, shit.
把槍給我
Give me the gun.
槍給我  露絲
Give me the gun, Ruth.
你這是干什么
What are you doing?
聽我說
Listen to me.
我們站起來  走出去
We're gonna stand up and walk out there.
-不好  -我先走
- No. - Okay. I'm gonna go first.
你跟著我  這事兒就這樣了
You come after me. That's how it's gonna be.
不  我們能脫身的
No. We can make it.
我們跑的話或許能逃掉
We can make it if we run.
-我們跑不掉的  -能行的
- We can't make it, Ruth. - Yeah, we can.
他們會開槍打死我們的
They're gonna shoot us.
如果我們待在這里
If we stay in here,
他們會當場打死我們的
they're gonna shoot us right where we are.
不要  求你了
No. Please.
我必須這么做
I'm gonna do it.
我不要  我不要坐牢
I'm not gonna do it. I'm not going to jail!
你跟他們說一切都是我干的
You got to tell them I did everything.
把所有事情推到我和弗雷迪身上
Tell them that me and Freddy did everything.
是我把槍放在你手里的
You got a gun in your hands 'cause I put it there.
告訴他們你嚇壞了
You tell them you were scared
于是我把槍給你了
and I put it there.
我坐不了幾年牢的
I'm gonna be out in a blink,
我很快就回來
and I'm gonna come back.
你等著我就行
All you got to do is wait for me.
我發誓我會回來找你的
I promise I'll come get you.
乖乖等我  好嗎
Just wait for me, okay?
等我
Just wait for me.
我兒子死了
So, I lost my boy.
現在只剩下你和鮑勃
And that leaves you and Bob.
只是鮑勃沒有選擇余地
Only Bob don't got a choice.
露絲  我實在搞不懂
I'm confused, Ruth.
我收留你們
I took you kids in,
把你和鮑勃當成自己的孩子
raised you and Bob like you were my own.
你們怎么能做出這種事情
How do you go and do a thing like this?
這不都是你教我們做的嗎
We were just doing what you taught us to do.
你懷的是男孩還是女孩
Is that a boy or a girl?
你知道了嗎
Do you know yet?
不知道
I don't know.
露絲  你準備怎么辦
So, what do you want to do, Ruth?
我會等他
I'm gonna wait for him.
親愛的露絲
Dear Ruth...
昨晚我又夢見你了
I dreamed about you again last night.
我對你可謂是
I guess I dream about you every night
日思夜想
and most days, too.
腦海中想到的都是你的面容
I hold your face in my mind.
耳朵里聽見的全是你的聲音
I put your voice together in my head.
我想象著你慢慢變長的秀發
I think about your hair getting longer.
和漸漸隆起的小腹
I think about your belly getting bigger.
監獄里有人為自己行為后悔
I hear people talk about regret,
不過我沒有絲毫悔意
but I haven't got any.
持槍搶劫
我對自己做過的事情不會太過糾結
I don't think poorly on the things I've done.
與露絲·格思里一起被人稱作"雌雄大盜"
被判25年徒刑
事情是我們做的
We did what we did,
我們就是這種人
and that is who we are.
你拿到信之前
They're gonna cross out this sentence
他們會刪掉這句話的
before you get to read it,
但是我相信你知道其中含義
but I know you know what it says.
每天早上起來
Every day,
我就想是不是今天能夠見到你
I wake up thinking today's the day I'm gonna see you,
那一天總會來臨的
and one of these days, it will be so.
我會一直給你寫信
And until then,
直到和你見面
I'll keep writing you.
每天都給你寫
I'll write you every day.
有一天你拿到信的時候
And someday you'll get a letter from me,
抬頭一瞥
and you will look up,
會發現送信的人正是我
and it'll be me who's handing it to you.
到那時無需文字傳情
And then we can forget about words,
我可以撫摸你的臉頰
and I'll touch your face
可以親吻你
and I'll kiss you.
鮑勃·馬爾登  你醒著嗎
Bob Muldoon, are you awake?
醒著
Yeah.
你有女兒了
You got a baby girl.
我會將女兒擁入懷中
And I'll take our baby girl in my arms.
然后我們離開
And we will ride off to somewhere...
遠走高飛
somewhere far away.
有空回信給我
Write to me soon, any chance you get.
愛你的鮑勃
Love, Bob.
媽媽  媽媽
Mommy. Mommy.
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
-你睡得好嗎  -很好
- How'd you sleep? - Good.
-你餓嗎  -不餓
- You hungry? - No.
怎么了  過來
What's up? Come here.
我們一起再睡會兒
Let's go back to sleep.
媽媽  看我找到什么了
Mommy! Look what I found!
-你找到什么了  -小貓咪
- What'd you find? - Kitties!
-它們從哪里來的  -不知道
- Where did these come from? - I don't know.
你們幾位啊
How many are you?
你們還很小呢
You're just a tiny little thing.
是不是啊小家伙
Aren't you tiny?
你們的媽媽呢
Where's your mama at?
你叫喚什么呢
What are you crying for? Huh?
-也許它想我抱  -什么
- Maybe he wants me. - What?
-也許它想我抱  -可能
- Maybe he wants me. - Maybe he does.
但你還有兩口沒吃完呢
But you still have two more bites.
小馬駒跑啊跑
"And the little horse ran and ran
狐貍追了上來
and foxes chased him,
他能聽見狐貍的叫喊聲
and he could hear them barking.
還有狼群在追他
And the wolves ran after him,
他能聽見狼在嚎叫
and he could hear them howling."
但他知道他們抓不到他的
"But he knew they couldn't catch him."
-熊  -是啊  一只小熊
- Bear. - Yeah, there's that baby bear.
你爸爸可喜歡熊了
Your daddy loves bears.
他過去常和熊一起摔跤
He used to wrestle with them.
把它們撲倒在地
He'd tackle them down.
給熊的鼻子上來上一拳
He'd bop them on the nose.
塞爾維  把鞋子穿上
Sylvie, put your shoes on.
好的
Okay.
-你好  -早上好  格思里小姐
- Hey. - Morning, Miss Guthrie.
我想你上班前找到你
I was hoping to catch you before work.
-出了什么事  -我能進門說嗎
- Is something wrong? - I was hoping for a word.
-你一共有幾只貓  -四只
- How many cats you got? - Four.
四只  這只叫什么名字
Four? What's this one's name?
薇洛
Willow.
它比較適合叫吉米
He looks like a Jimmy to me.
這些貓哪里來的
How'd you get those cats?
下來
Get down.
在后院撿到的
Found them out back.
謝謝
Oh, thank you.
貓媽媽估計早就走了
Mama was long gone, I guess.
你需要別人幫你養幾只嗎
Well, you need someone to take a few of them off your hands?
幾只貓我還是養得起的
I can handle some kittens, at least.
話說...
Like I said, uh...
他們準備讓你去警察局走一趟
They're setting to get ready to call you down to the station,
不久就會有鋪天蓋地的新聞了
and, uh, it's gonna be all over the news later.
我覺得這事還是由朋友告訴你比較好
Thought best if you hear this from a friend.
什么事
Hear what?
鮑勃已經5次越獄未遂了
Bob tried to escape five times already.
這事兒你知道嗎
Did you know that?
不知道
No, sir.
我還是跟你說吧
Well, maybe six times is the charm.
和他一起越獄的人
The boys he broke free with got caught
美國俄克拉何馬州東北部城市
在巴特爾斯維爾想爬火車北上
trying to hop a train up near Bartlesville,
結果被抓住了
heading north.
鮑勃可能也是這么干的
Maybe Bob's doing likewise.
也可能他早已跑遠了
Maybe he's already long gone.
可能吧
Maybe.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我不知道
I don't know.
有人打聽過他嗎
Anybody asking about him anybody at all?
沒有
Nope.
他信里沒提嗎
What about those letters?
信寄出前你們不是就讀過了
Everyone read them before they even got sent.
信里沒說什么
They don't say anything.
你能把信帶來嗎
You want to just bring them in anyway?
我悉聽尊便
I'll do whatever you want,
但是他不會回來的
but he won't come back.
他是不會像你們想的那樣為了我回來的
He's not coming back for me if that's what you're thinking.
露絲
Ruth!
她那有線索嗎
Did she tell you anything?
她告訴你什么了嗎
沒有  吉恩  她什么都沒說
No, Gene. She didn't say a damn thing.
真意外  我覺得她對你會比較說得開
I'm surprised. I thought she'd like you better than me.
格思里被捕
這事兒就交給我吧
Let me have this one, huh?
當然啦  是你挨了槍子
Well, hell, pat. You're the one he shot.
當然由你來抓那混蛋
I'm gonna let you catch the son of a bitch.
露絲·格思里無罪釋放
對不起我來晚了
Sorry I'm late.
她今天受罰了
She had to have a time-out.
她和邁爾斯打架了
She got in a fight with Miles.
你為什么和男孩子打架
Why did you get into a fight with those boys?
他們罵我
Because they called me names.
光憑這個理由可不行
You need to have a better reason than that.
來吧  沒事啦
Come on. Upsy-Daisy. Oy.
-晚上好  -你好
- Good evening. - Hi.
-小姑娘你好啊  -你好
- Hey, little girl. - Hi.
你今天真漂亮
Don't you look pretty today?
你是不是馬上過生日了
You got a birthday coming up, don't you?
想要什么生日禮物啊
Well, you got your birthday list put together yet?
你可以考慮考慮
You better get on that.
讓你媽媽幫你一起想
Get your mama to help you.
我聽新聞里說了
I heard the news.
你想談談嗎
Anything you want to talk about?
所有人都想從我這里找到線索
Everyone thinks I got something to tell them.
其實我真的無可奉告
I don't have a goddamn thing.
聽他們說已經追蹤他到蒙大拿州了
They say they traced him to Montana.
你覺得他在那里
You think he's in Montana?
我大可以打幾個電話通通關系
I can make some phone calls
看看能否把這事了結了
see what I can do about putting an end to all this.
我自己就能了結這一切
I could put an end to all this right now all by myself.
我只需要
All I'd have to do is...
說出真相就可以
tell the truth.
你好你好小藍鴉  為我來歌唱
Hey, little blue Jay, sing me a song?
歌唱那圣安娜  在圣安東尼奧
About Santa Ana at the San Anton'
你好你好小藍鴉  讓我偷偷親一下
Hey, blue Jay, can I steal a kiss?
就像偷走榴彈炮  在岡薩雷斯一樣
Like they tried to steal a Cannon from Gonzales?
藍鳥藍鳥  吹著口哨
Bluebird, whistle Waterloo?
我為你撐起蔭涼
Will you come to the bower
你要不要來享
I've shaded for you?
你好你好小藍鴉  為我來歌唱
Hey, little blue Jay, sing me a tune
回到六月的墨西哥  在那小路上
Down way in Mexico, back in June
女士  勞駕
Excuse me, ma'am.
女士
Ma'am?
沿著路繼續開
Keep driving and stick to the highway.
-我們在哪里  -什么
- Where are we, anyway? - What?
我們在哪里  在哪個州
Where are we? What state are we in?
-密蘇里州  -密蘇里嗎
- Missouri. - Oh, Missouri?
我知道你是誰了
I recognize you.
怎么開大聲點
Hey, how do you turn it up?
在旁邊  有一個...
On the side, there's a little, uh...
就是它
Yeah, that's it.
寂寞的夜
And lonely nights,
我思念你
I think of people that I miss.
每一天  我都在想你思念誰
And every day, I think of others you might miss.
你打算去哪里
Where you planning on going?
去個沒人去過的地方
A direction that hasn't been invented yet.
我不知道
I don't know.
我對你無法忘懷
I could never forget about you.
無論歡樂與悲傷
The good times and the bad.
那么
So...
你是怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
-做什么  越獄嗎  -是啊
- Do what... get out? - Yeah.
現在流行這個發型嗎
Is this how fellas are wearing their hair?
老兄  我是這么走出來的
Well, man, I just started walking,
就和我之前說的一樣
you know... just like I said I would.
就這么走出來的
And just walked out?
是的
Yep.
怎么走出來的
How's that work?
獄警們明天晚上都會來巡夜
Well, you know, the guards they come by your cell every night.
喊著"熄燈"
Sort of saying, "Lights out".
用警棍敲著欄桿
And rattling bars with their sticks.
有這么個獄警
And this one guard
喜歡開玩笑  和我們玩得開
he used to always joke and carry on with us.
有天晚上我對他說
And one night I said,
我們沒幾面可以見了
"Well, I won't be seeing you much longer.
我想我會在十天內出獄
I figure I'll be out of here in about 10 days."
他問  你怎么出獄
He said, "How you gonna do it?"
我說  就這么走出去啊
I said, "I'm gonna just walk right out the door."
他說他們會阻止我的
And he said they'd stop me.
然后我說  不行啊長官
And I said, "No, sir."
我有更重要的事要做
I've got better things to do.
他說  那也不行
And he said, "Well, that's not how it works."
我說
And I said, "Well,
有志者事竟成
it only works that way 'cause you think it has to.
上天在召喚我
See, I've got a higher calling.
我有老婆孩子
I've got a wife and a little girl
孩子需要爸爸
who needs her daddy."
然后他問我
And he asked me
怎么解釋上天的召喚
what I know about higher callings...
如果我出去
says even if I do get out,
我應該就我的所作所為
I'm gonna have to answer to God
向上帝和惡魔做出解釋
and the devil for the things I done.
我告訴他  該死
I tell him... Shoot.
我告訴他
I tell him...
我說  長官
I tell him, "Sir..."
過去的我是惡魔  現在我是個凡人
I used to be the devil. Now I'm just a man."
隨著日子一天天過去
As the days tick by...
10天  9天  8天...
到了最后一天
and on the last day,
監獄門開了
the bars open up,
我就這么走出來了
and I walk right out.
新聞里說你是跳車逃走的
News says you jumped off a work truck.
是的
Yeah.
好吧
Well...
你有吃的嗎
Man, have you got anything to eat?
我還有點餓
I'm still a little bit hungry.
我給你找找
Well, I'll find something.
你最近見過露絲嗎
Have you seen Ruth lately?
沒有  好久不見了
Nope. It's been a while.
她現在不和她媽一起住了
She don't live with her mama no more.
有了個新房子
Got a new house.
新房子
A new house?
斯克里特一直照顧她
Skerritt's been looking after her.
替她打理一切
He got her all set up.
或許我應該告訴你
Guess I should tell you
我前幾天接到個電話打聽你
got a call the other day asking about you.
是嗎  你怎么說的
Oh, yeah? What'd you tell 'em?
我說我沒見過你  實話實說嘛
I told them I hadn't seen you, which I hadn't.
沒想到那么快就見到你了
Didn't think I'd be seeing you so soon.
說真的
That's the truth.
這些錢
I guess that's about...
夠還我欠你的債了
that's about what I owe you.
這錢哪里來的
Where'd this come from?
哪都有
All over.
誰的錢
Whose is it?
我的
It's mine.
聽上去好像是木頭軟化了
Sounds like that wood's gone soft.
是啊  應該是
Yeah, I expect you're right.
再多釘子也架不住
More nails just won't hold it.
每次下雨
The whole gutter just comes off the house
排水槽都會掉下來
every time it rains like this.
我就爬上去重新釘好
You know, I go out there and nail it back up.
誰知道  轉眼又掉下來了
Next thing you know, it's back off.
有功夫釘排水槽
Well, you can either do that
你還不如多準備些水桶接水
or get more buckets.
是啊  好主意
Yeah, I could do that.
能解燃眉之急
That'd be easier in the short-term, for sure.
那樣的話
Then I'd have to haul that water out
每次下雨我都得往外倒水
every time it rains. I don't know.
-你好  -你好啊
- Howdy! - Howdy to you.
這場雨讓我想起
Yeah, all this rain we've been having reminds me of
我們那次行軍
that one march, it was.
每天只能前進十英尺
We'd get ten and a half inches in a day.
老兄
Man.
我那臺中型坦克基本沒油了
Oh, my middle tank out there has gone dry,
另兩臺也...
and the other two...
問下這是哪個鎮啊
Say, can you tell me just what town we're in, exactly?
默里迪恩[密西西比東部城市]
This is Meridian.
這樣啊
Okay.
我們剛從玫瑰谷[位于德州]過來
See, we passed through Glen Rose,
但沒看到什么路牌
but we didn't see a sign...
也不知道走過了沒有
didn't know if we'd gone to far, not far enough.
那得看你們去哪了
Well, that depends on where you're headed.
我們就來這
We're headed here.
你們要去獵鹿嗎
You, uh, plan to hunt some deer?
正打算著呢
Thinking about it.
那天下著暴雨
Anyway, it rained so much,
坦克都被淹了
it filled up them tanks,
轉天我老婆去檢查它們
and my wife walked up there to check 'em the next day,
里面還有條鯰魚
and there was catfish lyin' there.
坦克里全是雨水  還往外淌著
That thing filled up, and it was spillin',
魚順著水跑了出來
and it had come out in the spill.
-這是真的嗎  -你說什么
- Are these real? - Come again?
這槍是真的嗎
Are these real?
貨真價實
You bet.
哪年產的
How old are they?
那把手槍得有125年的歷史了
Well, that pistol goes back 125 years.
你瞎掰的吧
You don't say.
看到旁邊那張小紙條了嗎
See that scrap of paper there next to it?
那是一張名單
That there is a list...
寫著所有死在
of every poor son of a bitch
這把槍口下的人名
who met his end at the barrel of it.
聽起來真是忽悠
Sounds like a bunch of bullshit to me.
也許吧
Yeah, probably is.
你們想買點什么
Can I help you gentlemen find something in particular?
就隨便轉轉
Nah. Just looking around.
有新消息嗎
Is there any news?
今天沒有
No, not today.
也許你需要這些
Figured you want these back.
上面都是灰塵
They're just gathering dust.
-你讀過嗎  -沒有  夫人
- You read 'em? - No, ma'am.
為什么  誰都想看
Why not? Everyone else has.
我不應該看
They're not mine to read.
能問你個問題嗎
Can I ask you something?
當然
Mm, sure.
你說鮑勃
Do you mean what you said about
不會回來找你  是嗎
Bob not coming back for you?
是的
Yeah, I did.
你是不是想等這件事平息了
Well, I was thinking maybe you all'd want to
就搬離這里
get out of town until all this blows over.
你是說等他被抓到之后嗎
You mean till he gets caught?
我們還能去哪
Where would we go?
安全的地方
Someplace safe.
你也來嗎
Would you come?
會有人和你一起
Someone would come with you.
我會一直住在這里吧
I think I'll just stay here. You know,
我得工作
I got to work,
賽爾維也要過生日了
and Sylvie's got her birthday.
我們會好好生活
We'll be just fine.
是呀  她快四歲了
Yeah, sure. She's gonna be 4.
-對吧  -是的
- Is that right? - Yep.
她想要什么禮物呢
Yeah. What's she want?
-她想要匹馬  -真的馬嗎
- She wants a horse. - Like, a real horse?
-是的  -好吧
- Yep. - Yeah?
你把馬養在哪呢
Where you gonna put it?
我倒認識個人
You know what? I know a man who...
可以從他那買一只  價格還算公道
who could sell you one for... for not a bad price.
-真的嗎  -真的
- You do? - I do.
可惜我養不了馬
I can't take care of no horse.
養不了馬  也許
Well... No horse. Maybe I could,
我能給她送點別的禮物
maybe I could bring her something.
怎么講
Why?
我最近在整理家
Well, I was just doing some cleaning, and...
收拾出來一堆小玩意
I... I may have a few deals just floating around that maybe,
也許里面有她喜歡的
uh... maybe she'd take to, you know? Just...
-小玩意  -嗯  就是些小東西
- A few deals, huh? - A few deals.
親愛的露絲
Dear Ruth...
我不知道這封信該如何開頭
I don't know how to start this letter.
我有萬千思緒
I have got a million things on my mind,
需要釋放
and I need to get them out.
你應該知道我越獄了
I know you know I am out,
希望你知道我要去找你了
and I hope you know I am coming for you,
正如我一直所說的那樣
just like I always said.
正如我答應你的那樣
Just like I always said I was going to do,
我要去找你
I am coming for you.
我多希望能在你的身旁
I wish I were standing at your side,
與你耳鬢廝磨  但現實并非如此
whispering in your ear, but that's not so.
我光著腳
I came across the woods and mountains
穿過樹林翻過高山
with no shoes on.
長途跋涉  現在已經很近了
I traveled high and far, and now I am close.
近在咫尺
I'm so close to you.
近到幾乎可以碰觸到你的臉頰
I can almost reach out and touch your cheek.
給你  唐
Here you go, Don.
你們放松下吧
You boys take it easy, now.
你說你啊  鮑勃
Well... Look at you, Bob.
越了獄就往這兒跑
Break out of parson and head straight back here.
這可不太明智吧
Maybe not the smartest move.
只要你不告發我
Long as you don't turn me in.
邁爾斯呢
Where's Miles?
邁爾斯走了
Miles is gone.
-走了  -格拉迪斯也走了
- Gone? - Gladys is gone, too.
-現在就剩我了  -那誰管展覽
- It's just me now. - Well, who's running the show?
沒有展覽了
No show to run... not anymore.
這不是弗雷迪的嗎
Didn't this belong to Freddy?
我也不知道
Doubt it.
我還記得一起玩這個
I remember playing with this.
還有其他許多印第安小人
And all those little Indians...
其他的小人你放哪里了
have you got those Indians someplace?
弗雷迪的那些老古董都找不見了
Anything of Freddy's is long gone.
鮑勃  你想要什么
What do you want, Bob?
你沒聽說嗎
I was just wondering if you'd heard anything.
聽說什么
About what?
這地方有個家伙越獄了
About that local man who escaped from the penitentiary.
前幾天吉恩·丹得勒和他幾個手下
Gene Dentler and a bunch of his deputies
來找我聊了聊
come over a few days ago for a chat.
我告訴他們至少有六個家伙
I told them I could think of at least six sons of bitches
想看你死翹翹
who've got a mind to see you dead.
相比之下  還是坐下來賭一把
But that it'd be more fun to
看誰最先抓到你  應該更有意思
sit back and take bets on who gets you first.
那時你真是把身邊的朋友得罪光了
You fucked over your share of people in your day.
是啊  所以我才被抓住
Yeah, and then I got caught.
但不是被他們抓住的
Not by them, you didn't.
他們還是別找我了
Well, they might as well quit looking.
老鮑就要消失了
Old Bob Muldoon's about to disappear.
那準備消失到哪去呢
And where's old Bob Muldoon gonna disappear to?
我想要安頓下來
I'm thinking about settling down,
建個小房子  開個店鋪
build a little house, open a shop.
我不知道
I don't know.
慢慢變老  像你一樣
Get old. Like you.
自己一人嗎
On your own?
聽說你給了露絲一套房子
Oh. So, I heard you bought Ruth a house.
我把一間老房讓給她住
I'm letting her stay in one of my old places.
帶一個大院子
It's got a big old yard
足夠她女兒玩的
where her little girl can play.
那也是我的女兒
Hey, that's my little girl, too.
老兄  我告訴你
Man, I'll tell you...
她現在太可愛  你拿她真沒辦法
she's about cute enough to make you want to give up.
我承認  你這樣做得對
You did one thing right. I'll give you that.
我盡全力去照顧她們兩個
I do what I can to look after both of them.
是啊
Yeah.
接下來輪到我好好照顧她們了
Well, I guess I'll handle it from here.
-你這么想嗎  -是的
- Oh, you think so? - Yes, sir.
我告訴你
Well, I'll tell you what.
你愛干什么干什么
You do whatever you want.
帶上你的錢
You take all your money,
走得越遠越好
and you get yourself as far away from here as you possibly can.
但你聽好了
But you listen to me when I tell you...
離她們遠點
You leave those girls alone.
我做不到
I can't do that.
你可以的
Yeah, you can.
那為什么我要離開
And why would I?
仔細想想  鮑勃
Well, now, think about it, Bob.
你會給她們帶來多少麻煩
If you got any trouble coming your way...
她們肯定不想找麻煩
They sure as hell don't need that.
什么麻煩
What trouble is that?
你已經出獄了
You got out.
你還想得到什么
What more do you want?
我想要我的家人
I want my family.
我也是  但我已經沒有家人了
So do I. But I don't got it.
我們這么辦
Now, this is how it works.
我不會比現在傷你更多了
I will never hurt you more than I'm hurting you now.
我不會再對你動手
I will never lay another hand to you
不會扎你的手指  或是擰你的臉蛋
or prick your finger or pinch your cheek.
我不會報警
I won't call the sheriff,
也不會告訴他們你在哪
and I won't tell them where you've been.
但只要讓我知道
But if I hear that old Bob Muldoon
老鮑還聯系露絲
has been talking to Ruth Guthrie...
你就是自找麻煩
You asked me about trouble.
我保證麻煩會找到你頭上
I will make sure you got some.
那天是弗雷迪先開的槍
Freddy was the one who shot first that day.
如果他沒這樣做
Nobody would have gotten hurt
誰都不會受到傷害
if he hadn't done that.
走吧  鮑勃
Go on, Bob.
我去開門了
I got to unlock my door.
趁沒人看到你  快走
Get out of here before someone sees you.
找個安全的地方吧
Find yourself someplace safe.
鑰匙在哪
Where are the keys?
-在車子里  -鑰匙
- In the truck. - The keys?
我會給她帶來麻煩嗎
I'm gonna give her trouble?
就他能給她買房子嗎
He thinks he can buy her a house?
-不是  -我才不管他那套
- No, sir. - I don't think that's how it works.
露絲會像逃離火災一樣  逃離那間房子
Ruth will walk away from that house like it was on fire.
筆  給我來支筆
Pen... I need a pen.
給我筆
Give me a pen.
該死
No damn sense.
親愛的露絲
不好意思
Excuse me.
親愛的露絲  我不知道如何開頭
我在離你很近的地方  我們該走了
...撫摸你的臉頰...我們明晚見  日出就出發
我們養活自己...去我爸的農場...
你我還有賽爾維一起...我們該走了
過來
Come here.
我計劃
I was thinking...
我們可以來個旅行
Maybe we could go on a trip...
等你過完生日
After your birthday.
你覺得怎樣
What do you think about that...
去個新地方
going someplace new?
坐在車里  一直往前開
Just get in the car and drive and drive.
很有意思
Be real fun.
別跑
Hey, hold on.
讓我看看
Let me see that.
給我
Give it here.
走吧
There you go.
快走
Come on. Go.
我把店關了
What do you think about me closin' up...
帶你去兜一圈怎么樣
take you for a ride somewhere..
逃離一下
Get away for a little bit?
伙計  最近好嗎
Hey, sweetie. How you been?
還好
Just fine.
-我犯法了還是怎么著  -沒有
- Break the law or something? - No.
感覺好久沒見到你了
I just hadn't seen you around in years, it feels like.
我一直在這
I stay put.
-要來一杯嗎  -不了  謝謝
- You want something to drink? - No, sir. Thank you.
我們在找你的一個老朋友
We're looking for an old friend of yours.
-你肯定聽到消息了  -是的
- I'm sure you heard the news. - Yeah. Yeah.
幾天前就有從門羅來的警察問過我
A couple cops came by from Monroe's asking questions.
好  你見過他嗎
All right. Have you seen him?
當然沒有
Sure haven't.
好吧
Look, all right.
你介意我到處看看嗎
You mind if I take a look around?
比利  看下吧臺
Billy, mind the bar?
要檢查就快點
Hope we can make this quick.
別打擾到我的顧客
Don't want to rile up my customers.
從去年冬天就再沒他的音信了
Haven't heard from him since last winter.
他給我寄過一封信
He sent me a letter.
-你回信了嗎  -沒有
- You write him back? - Nope.
你是不和鮑勃·馬爾登
Weren't you part of his old gang...
露絲·格思里  弗雷迪一伙的嗎
Bob Muldoon, Ruth Guthrie, Freddy?
不了  早不干了
Nope. Got out of that racket.
我開了這家酒吧
Got myself this business.
該死  我把鑰匙忘樓下了
Hell. Left the darn key downstairs.
等我一下
Well... Hold up.
我要快點回前臺  不能離開太久
I'm gonna need to get back to the register before too long.
我當書簽用的
Been using it as a bookmark.
這下我不知道看到哪頁了
I guess I lost my place.
露絲給你的嗎
Ruth give it to you?
她寄來的
She mailed it.
想讓我寄給鮑勃
Asked me, uh... asked me to send it on to Bob.
你沒有寄
You never did.
我說過  我不太會寄信
Like I said, I'm bad with correspondence.
多久的事了
How long ago?
小姑娘幾歲了來著
How old's the little girl?
三歲  快四歲了
那就這么長時間了
About that long, then.
好吧
Okay.
-這個我帶走可以嗎  -隨你
- Uh, mind if I hang on to this? - By all means.
如果有消息就給我們打電話
I'm sure you'll call us if you hear anything.
當然
Sure bet.
看
Look at this.
這是你穿的第一件衣服
This is the first thing you ever wore,
在你出生那天
the day you were born.
你那時好小
You were so tiny.
看看多小啊
Look how small it is.
我抱著你回家  你睡了好久好久
I brought you home, and you slept and slept for hours.
你真是個好女孩
You were such a good little girl.
我們把它帶上
I'll bring this with us just because...
也許我們有天會用到它
We might need it someday.
小馬撿起它的鞋子
"And the little horse picked up his shoes
一口氣跑出黑暗的樹林
and ran until he was out of the dark woods.
他跑到小魚的河中
He came to the river where the fish had been.
小魚已經離開了
The fish was gone now, and
沒有人能阻止他過河
there was no one there to stop him from crossing.
他穿越河流  翻越山脈
He crossed the river and climbed the hill,
沒多久  就回到了家
and before too long, he could see home."
寶貝  怎么了  你好安靜
What's wrong, sweet girl? Why are you so quiet?
一切都會好起來的
Everything's gonna be fine.
只需靜候  好嗎
You just wait and see, okay?
親愛的鮑勃
你有鮑勃的消息嗎
Have you heard from Bob?
-為什么不進來坐下  -不了
- Why don't you come in? - No.
我知道鮑勃就在附近
I know Bob's been around.
你把這個給他好嗎
Will you see to it that he gets this?
這是什么
What is it?
你想看就看吧  反正你都會去看的
You can read it if you want. I figure you will anyway.
如果你見到他  能告訴他
If you see him... Can you tell him...
算了  給他就好了
Just... just give it to him.
親愛的鮑勃
Dear Bob...
希望你永遠收不到這封信
I hope you never get this.
我希望你走過那扇門
I want you to come through that door,
帶我們離開  一如你所承諾
take us away just like you always said.
但你不能
But you can't.
你不能來這里  至少現在不行
You can't come here... not right now.
我也不能跟你走
And I can't go with you.
一旦你來  你就會被抓住
If you come here, they'll catch you.
如果我們一起走
If we go with you,
他們也會找到我們
they'll find us.
結局不該如此
It can't end like that.
我不允許有這種結局  無論對我們
I can't let it end like that, not for us...
還是對賽爾維
And not for Sylvie.
我不能讓這種事發生
I can't let that happen.
所以  我們會離開
So, we're gonna go.
你來找我們時  我們已經不在了
If you come looking for us here, we'll be gone.
我們會去一個誰都不認識我們的地方
I'll go somewhere where no one knows who we are,
或者  我們可以耐心等待
or we can wait for the time
直到整個世界都將我們忘記
to be right and the world to forget about us.
我不知道如何表達
I don't know how to explain this any better,
但我知道你能理解我的意思
but I know you know what I'm talking about.
我們已經等了很久
We've waited so long.
只需再多等一陣子
We've just got to wait a little longer.
你就能來找我們了
Come find us.
我知道你會來的
I know you will.
希望你會  我們會重逢的
I hope you will. We'll find each other.
我深深愛著你
I love you so much. I do.
該起床了  寶貝
It's time to wake up, baby girl.
小甜豆
Sweet pea...
早上好
Good morning.
生日快樂
Happy Birthday.
你見過他嗎
You seen him?
我們去過他女朋友家了
We stopped by his girl's place.
哈蒂根說如果見到你
Hartigan said to tell you something
告訴你件事
if we ran into you.
什么事
What's that?
該死  我忘了
Shit, I forgot.
還是我告訴你吧
Let me tell you something.
你拿著它該干嘛干嘛
You take that and do what you will.
如果沒找到他
And if you don't find him,
也別回來
that don't give you cause to come back here.
明白嗎
You understand?
別以為我不管這事了
Don't think I'm washing my hands off all this.
如果你們再敢踏進小鎮一步
And if you set foot in this town again,
哪怕只是有牽扯她們的想法
if you even think about bringing those girls into this,
我都會殺了你們
I'll kill you.
就這樣
And that'll be that.
老兄
Dude.
沃倫·米勒
Warren Miller.
誰編的這些名字
Who makes up the names?
不是編的  都是真人
They ain't made up. They're real folks.
都死了  但是...都是真的
I mean, they're dead, but... they're real.
真的嗎
Oh, really?
聽別人說的
So I'm told.
-露絲和賽爾維也是嗎  -是的
- Ruth and Sylvie too? - Yes.
-不會再有人跟著我們吧  -不會了
- Nobody's gonna be asking after us? - Not anymore.
好樣的
Good job.
許愿了嗎  許的什么愿
You make a wish? What did you wish for?
不能告訴你
I'm not telling.
好吧  還有小秘密呢
All right. You keep your little secret, huh?
我看起來如何
How do I look?
和原來一樣
You look like you.
那就好
Then that'll do.
看來我沒有虛度光陰
The way I see it, I didn't waste my time.
-記得老喬嗎  -記得
- You remember old Joe Cranston? - Yep.
記得他跟我去圣路易斯那次嗎
Remember that time he and I went up to St. Louis?
在我們出發前
He spent about three hours getting prettied up
他早起了三個小時打扮
before we got in the car to go up there.
我說  喬  你干嘛呢
I said, "Joe, what are you doing?"
他說  萬一我出了什么事
He said, "Well, in case anything happens to me,
我希望媽媽還能認出我來
I want to make sure my mama can recognize me."
他穿上那件他十二歲時就在穿的外套
So he put on this coat he had when he was 12 years old,
系扣子時  由于他個頭太大
and he tried to button it up, and he was a big old boy,
外套從后背撕開了
and it ripped right out the back.
他就一直穿著那玩意兒
And he kept that thing on all the way
從圣路易斯再到德克薩斯
up to St. Louis and back down to Texas.
像個邋遢鬼
He looked like a damn raggedy Ann.
等回來時  我說
And when we got back, I said,
喬  即便你出事了
"Joe, you know your mama would have recognized you
你媽媽也能認出你的
if something happened to you."
他說  對啊  因為我穿了這件外套
He said, "Yeah, 'cause I had my coat on."
他沒懂我意思
I mean, he didn't get it.
人們...
You see, people...
好多事都不懂  卻自以為是
they don't know things the way that they think they know them.
賽爾維...她會認出我的
Sylvie... she's gonna know me.
她都不用看就能認出我
She'll know me without looking at me.
露絲...我在街上她就能感覺到
And Ruth... by God, she'll feel me coming down the street.
我們一直是...
I mean, we always just been...
另一個彼此
You know, just two parts of the same.
我們也會吵得不可開交
I mean, we would fight,
就像兩個孩子搶一個皮球
and we'd fight like two kids with a ball.
她會發脾氣  把家里搞得底朝天
And she'd rip through the house like she was on fire,
而我卻只想抱住她
and I'd just want to hold her.
我只想抱住她
I'd just want to hold her.
她會大吵大鬧  發瘋失控
But she'd be yelling and flapping around so quick,
像只蜂鳥一樣暴躁
it was like a hummingbird.
而我會說  露絲
I'd say, "Ruth
你就沖我吼吧  吼到嗓子啞了為止
you can scream at me till your voice is gone.
反正都一樣
But it doesn't make much difference.
當你喊夠了
Because when you're all done screaming,
我還是會陪你坐在房間里
it's just gonna be you and me sitting here in a room."
她說  是啊
And she said, "That's right.
我們永遠都在一起
It's always just gonna be the two of us."
多漂亮啊  喜歡嗎
Look how pretty that is. You like that?
生日快樂
Happy Birthday.
還有最后一個驚喜了
Well, there's, uh, one last surprise, I suppose.
知道怎么打開嗎
You know how to open this?
來打開吧
All right. Let's open her up. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
我得到它時  也像你這么大
So, this was mine when I was about your size.
看看你拿著什么樣
Let's see how it looks on you.
-替我向露絲問好  -我會轉告的
- Say hi to Ruth for me? - I'll tell her.
或許不要再見比較好
I guess I hope I never see you again.
-小狗怎么叫  -汪汪
- How's a dog sound? - Ruff, ruff.
汪汪  試試看
Ruff, ruff? Try that.
汪汪  小貓呢
Ruff, ruff, and then go back to cat.
試試看
Try that.
有人翻山越嶺
And some will travel 'cross the land,
只為找尋愛人
looking for their love
再來一次
One more time.
有人凝視大海  仰望天空
Others gaze upon the sea and search the sky above
可我不這樣
But count me not among them
那已是過往
As I was before
因為我早已
Now I go wandering
不再流浪
Wandering no more
如主所見  我不再流浪
I shall go wandering no more, my lord
我不再流浪
I shall go wandering no more
因為你就是
You are all the treasure
我找尋多時的寶藏
That I've been searching for
我不會再流浪
I shall go wandering no more
為什么不練練呢
Why don't you hang on to this?
一周后我再來看你
Maybe in a week or so, I'll check back in with you,
那時說不定你就能給我彈歌了
and maybe you'll play me a song.
-怎么樣  -不要
- How's that? - No.
-不要  -我明天要去旅行
- No? - I'm going on a trip tomorrow.
旅行  真的
A trip? Is that right?
她真棒
She's great.
你還好吧
You all right?
我很好啊
Yeah, I'm fine.
你來這兒干什么
What are you doing here?
抱歉我沒想打擾你的
Well, I didn't mean to wear out my welcome.
不  我只是問問
No. I just want to know.
我就是很愿意來
Just happy to be here.
你要離開嗎
You're planning on leaving?
-是的  -好吧
- Yes, I am. - All right.
去哪里
You know where you're headed?
不知道  我只想離開這里
No, I don't know yet... just away from here.
-如果需要幫助  -我什么都不需要
- Well, if you need any help... - I don't need anything.
謝謝你的邀請
I appreciate the invitation,
祝你晚安
and I bid you good night.
晚安
Good night.
露絲
Ruth.
我想告訴你一件事
I want to tell you something.
這些話  我憋了很久了
This has been, uh, weighing on me for some time.
在醫院時
Uh... When I was in the hospital,
我不是
I wasn't,
我不是在策劃還是什么的
I wasn't sitting there making plans or anything.
我從沒想過跟鮑勃對著干
You know, I got nothing against Bob.
而那天發生的事  那種風險本來就有
And what happened... I mean, that's the risk.
是我工作的一部分
That's... that's part of my job.
除此之外
And beyond that,
我沒有因為他的為人
I don't hold it against him
或是所作所為  對他懷恨在心
to be who he was or do what he was doing,
現在也沒有  我很高興能活著
and I still don't. I'm glad to be alive.
很高興認識你
I'm glad to know you.
如果你未曾經歷那些過去
And if you weren't who you were
未曾和他海誓山盟
and had never been with him
而我們依然相逢于此
and somehow we had still come together right here, right now,
我的感覺也不會改變
I wouldn't feel any different.
明白嗎
Do you understand?
你還記得那天嗎
You remember that day?
我記得自己挨了一槍
I remember getting shot.
就好像肩膀被打了一拳
I remember feeling like I'm getting punched in the shoulder,
仰望著德州悠遠的天空
seeing the big old Texas sky.
我都記得
I remember that,
-但是...  -你看見我了嗎
- but, uh... - Did you see me?
沒有
No, ma'am.
聽見我后來說的話了嗎
Did you hear what I said after?
我看了你的供詞
I read your statement.
那不完全屬實
It wasn't all true, you know.
我不是個昏頭昏腦的小女生
I wasn't just a little girl who got dragged in over her head.
我知道我做了什么
I knew what I was doing.
我想...
Well... I think that,
許多所言并非事實
a lot of things were said that might not have been true.
但你就那樣做了  他也是
But you did what you did. So did he.
無論你做過什么
And whatever it is you've done,
當我看見你和你女兒時
when I see you with your daughter
我眼中只有幸福
all I see is good.
或許我只是在耍你
Maybe I'm just fooling you.
是嗎
Are you?
等等  等等  該死
Wait. Wait, God damn it!
該死
God damn it.
你沖我開槍
You shot me.
為什么
Why'd you shoot me?
-我沒見過你  -是的  先生
- I've never even seen you. - No, sir.
那為什么  錢嗎
What's this about... money?
你  就因為你
You... it's about you.
你和那個女孩兒
You and the girl.
你們想做的一切
Everything you tried to do.
你要開槍嗎
You gonna shoot me?
我不想讓你覺得我欠你什么
I don't want you to think I owe you anything.
你沒有
No, you don't.
我惟一有所虧欠的人就是鮑勃
The only person I owe anything to is Bob.
不是的
That's not so.
這些事我一直壓在心里
I've been storing things up all this time,
徹夜不眠
sitting awake at night,
反復想著要對他說的話
thinking of all the things I want to say to him.
現在發生那么多的事
Except now I have so many things,
我都不知道從何說起
I don't know how I'd ever start.
我只有賽爾維和我自己
All I had was Sylvie and I.
我都不知道怎么在信里寫
I didn't know how to write about her.
換做你會怎么寫
How do you write about something like that?
我記得她出生的那天
I remember the day she was born.
我嚇壞了
I was so scared, and
我試圖阻止她的到來  可她還是來了
I tried to keep her from coming, but she came anyway.
他們把她送到我懷里時
And when they put her in my arms,
我們彼此對視
we just stared at one another,
我就覺得  為這樣的愛死掉也罷
and I thought I would die from all that love.
我想在信里跟他描述
And I tried to write to him about it
讓他也能體會那種感覺  但是...
so he'd know what it was like, but...
我找不到合適的詞語
but I just couldn't find the words to do it right.
所以我就不再...不再寫信
So, I just stopped... stopped writing to him.
我想見面時再講給他
I figured that I'd just tell him all at once when I saw him.
待他走進那道門
He'd walk through the door,
我就會知道如何講述
and I'd know exactly what to say to him,
一切也會回歸正軌
and things would be the way they used to be.
所以我留著每樣小東西
That's why I've been saving every little thing.
四年了  我一直沒睡好
And I haven't slept in four years.
我累了
And I'm tired.
我太累了
I'm just so goddamn tired.
那就歇歇
Then rest.
你會陪我等嗎
Will you wait with me while I do?
你還好吧
Are you all right? Okay?
你要...你要干什么
Hey, what are you... what are you doing?
開車  快開車
Drive, man. Drive.
-鑰匙歸你  -加油
- Please, just take the keys. - Step on the gas, man!
加足油門
Step on the gas!
好吧
All right.
沿著公路走
And just stick to the highway.
走到6號公路時右轉
When you get to highway 6, you turn right.
我...我只想見見我的家人
I... I'm just trying to go see my family,okay?
我不過是想回家
I'm just trying to get home.
我不想打架  都按你說的來
I ain't gonna put up a fight. I'll do whatever you want.
我只想回家見家人
I just want to make sure I get home to them.
我只想搭一下你的車
I just want you to drive.
你家什么樣
What's your family?
什么
What?
你家都有誰
What family have you got?
有妻子孩子嗎
You have a wife and kids?
沒有
No.
我是去看望父母
No, I'm going to see my parents.
你父母
Your parents?
-你爸媽  -是的
- Mom and dad? - Yeah.
你叫什么
What's your name?
-威爾  -你叫威爾
- Will. - Will's your name?
是的
Yeah.
威爾  有喝的嗎
Will, do you have anything to drink?
沒有
No.
You don't?
該死
Shoot.
我該去找點兒水的
I could go for some water.
你要去...醫院嗎
You need to... you need to go to a hospital or something?
不要
No, man.
沿著公路開  在6號公路拐彎
Just stay on the highway. Turn at highway number 6.
好的
Yes, sir.
你應該看出來我中彈了
Well, I guess you can tell I got shot. Yep.
那些人來抓我
These men came looking for me.
想把我干掉
They wanted to put me under.
有人派他們  他們就來了
Somebody sent them, and they came from somewhere,
他們找到我了
and they got me.
抓住我了
They got me pretty good.
不過沒弄死我
They didn't get me good enough.
看吧
See.
告訴你爸爸今天載了誰
Tell your daddy who you gave a ride to today.
好的
Okay.
誰
Who?
什么
What?
你是誰
Who are you?
放下槍
Drop it!
沒事了
It's all right.
你記得
You remember...
你第一次為我做事嗎
Remember the first run you ever did for me?
你和弗雷迪
Heh. You and Freddy.
第一次
The very first one.
我從沒為您做過什么  先生
Nah, I never did nothing for you, sir.
你倆都覺得自己很厲害
You both thought you were so tough.
其實都是小孩子而已
You were little boys.
我想回家
I want to go home.
十分鐘前我給摩根打了電話
I was on the line with Morgan 10 minutes ago,
告訴他發生了什么
told him how it happened.
不  不  不  你再打
No, no, no. You get 'em back on the phone
一直打到他們來
'till they come down here.
我不知道誰對誰干了什么
I don't know who did what to who.
查到身份了嗎
Did you get an I.D. yet?
沒有  但是...
No. I mean, yeah, but...
他不過是布魯森附近的混混吧
he was just some son of a bitch up near Bruleson.
誰知道呢
Who knows?
斯凱里特死的太狼狽了
Skerritt went out like a sucker, huh?
我送露絲回家
I'm gonna take Ruth on home.
不用  我讓泰迪去了
No, I got Teddy doing that.
還是我去吧
Yeah, I'm gonna take her.
等一下
Wait here.
沒事的  沒事  沒事
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
我去叫救護車
I'm gonna call an ambulance.
我一直在等你
I've been waiting for you.
住手  很癢的
Stop it. That tickles.
對胎兒不是應該唱唱歌什么的嗎
I thought that's what we're supposed to do... sing to 'em.
就說說話吧
Just talk.
那我來跟你講
Well... Let me tell you about something.
我來跟你講講未來的樣子
I'm gonna tell you about the future.
很久很久以后
In the future,
我很老很老
I'm a very old man.
我站在門口
And I'm standing in the door.
我們的房子門口
We're in a house.
那是我們的房子  離這兒很遠
It's our house, somewhere far away from here,
綠草成茵  夕陽西下
where everything is green and the sun is almost set.
我們駐足
And where we're standing,
仿佛在招手
the way I see it, we're waving to somebody.
也許正是向你招手
And maybe that somebody is you,
你走了那么久  終于回來看我們了
come to see us after a long time gone.
若真是你
If it is you...
我們很高興能與你相見
We are very happy to see you.
寶貝
Hey, sweetie.
再跟我講講那房子
Tell me more about that house.
我沒在和你說話
I'm not talking to you.
很大很大  是個農場吧
It's big. Maybe a farm.
很古老  比我們還老
It's old. It's older than us.
我還覺得那好像是我建的
At the same time, though, I feel like maybe I built it.
不好說
There's no telling.
真不好說啊
There's just no telling.
他們非圣人